kinto behr

data scientist

PERSONAL PROFILE

I am a data scientist and statistician with expertise in R and a keen interest in process automation, package development, and applied statistics. Although I am most comfortable in R, I have varying degrees of experience with a number of other languages from SQL (fluent), through Python, LaTeX, HTML/CSS and JavaScript (intermediate), to C++ (beginner).

Outside of work, I am an active contributor to the open source software community, having developed or made large contributions to a number of R packages. More information and an expanded resume are available at https://kinto-b.github.io

EMPLOYMENT HISTORY

Statistician

Social Research Centre | 2022 - Present

I am currently situated in the statistical methods team, where I am involved in broadly two kinds of work. On the one hand, I carry out statistical procedures like survey weighting, bias assessment, and non-response analysis. On the other hand, I am responsible for streamlining and automating data processing, analysis and reporting pipelines. Some of the things I have worked on in this latter capacity are

- Redesigning the SQL database and associated workflows that underpin the Life in Australia study
- Automating and standardising our survey weighting procedure
- Developing a Shiny application with SQL-based user-management for multi-client reporting of small area estimates

Data Scientist

Social Research Centre | 2020 - 2022

I was the lead data scientist on the SES, which approaches hundreds of thousands of higher education students each year. In this capacity, I was responsible for maintaining the data infrustructure throughout the full length of the pipeline from sample collection and validation, through fieldwork operations and data processing, to report production.

In addition, I made key contributions to the in-house R package architecture and Shiny application suite. In particular, I

- Authored and/or maintained the majority of in-house packages
- Trained other data scientists in R package development, helping them to become maintainers in their own right
- Developed a number of complex Shiny applications which became core to projects across the business, including one which won a company-wide competition

Team Lead

Sidekicker | 2018 - 2020

I was in charge of the community operations team, which was responsible for ensuring that the application marketplace was running smoothly. Alongside managing 15+ casual staff, I performed data analysis using SQL and Python, and automated core processes to save 100hrs of labour-time per month.

EDUCATION

Master of Statistics

University of New South Wales | 2021-2023

- Completed the first half of this qualification as a GDA at the University of Melbourne
- Thesis title: TBA
- UNSW WAM: 93% so far; UniMelb GPA: 4.0 (WAM: 88%)

Bachelor of Arts (Honours)

University of Melbourne | 2019

- · Recieved the Hastie Prize for graduating top of my class
- Thesis title: Epistemic Relativism: The Futility of the Argument from the Criterion
- GPA: 4.0 (WAM: 87%)

Bachelor of Arts and Bachelor of Science

Monash University | 2013 - 2017

- Received numerous academic awards including the Peter J. Lloyd prize in Theoretical Physics, the Dean's List Fellowship Award and five best in unit awards for achieving top marks across various physics courses
- Majors (minors): Philosophy (Japanese) and Physics (Mathematics)
- GPA: 3.93 (WAM: 87%)

SELECTED HONOURS

- 2019 Hastie Prize in Philosophy, the University of Melbourne
- 2016 Peter J. Lloyd Prize in Theoretical Physics, Monash University